I just rewatched Save the Last Dance, and this movie needs to be studied.
Sarah is a dancer in high school, and her mom dies in a car accident on the same day as her failed Juilliard audition.
So she quits dance, moves to the south side of Chicago to live with her estranged father, and go to an all-black high school.
And she's got like three months left of her high school career, so it doesn't make any sense.
Shanil sees Sarah at the first day of school, and she's like, oh my god, this white girl is not going to survive.
Sarah's like, oh my god, what is that?
Hip-hop? You don't say.
In gym class, Sarah shows off her dancing skills on the balance beam that every inner-city school has.
So Shanil's like, where'd you get those moves?
And Sarah's like, I used to be a dancer, not a big deal.
So Shanil invites her to Steps, an invite-only nightclub for serious dancers.
Also coming to Steps is Shanil's brother, Derek, who tells Sarah that she better be prepared for some, like, hardcore dancing.
This is the dancing at the club.
This is the members-only, invite-only dance club.
Like, you have to be a serious dancer for this.
You have to be a jabberwocky to be here, okay?
Derek starts dancing with Sarah, who's very white, and everybody knows it.
It was at this point where I was like, okay, who actually wrote this?
This man.
This is the guy.
And now it all makes sense.
Then Derek gives Sarah hip-hop lessons, which include learning how to crip-walk and sitting in a chair.
Then Sarah does one of these, and he's like, where'd you learn how to do that?
She's like, I used to be a dancer.
I don't want to talk about it.
She spends this whole movie begging for people to ask her about dance.
Derek convinces her to dance again and audition for Juilliard again, and he is going to help with the hip-hop.
I don't know.
Maybe don't audition.
Then she returns to the club.
I can't.
She returns back to the club, blacker than ever.
Look at her go.
They're chanting their names.
Sarah auditions for Juilliard, and she falls again and has to start over.
But Derek, who has been watching from the back of the auditorium, is like, not my baby girl.
So he runs up on stage and tells her he believes in her.
Then she does hip-hop for Juilliard.
I bet they've never seen that before.
They are so impressed.
They're like, she is so urban.
She's like, wait till you see what I do with the chair.
You didn't see that coming, did you?
They're like, oh, that girl is good.
Look at those gang signs.
Welcome to Juilliard.
Immediately admits her to Juilliard.
He's like, I know talent when I see it.
And it fulfills our diversity quota.